Correct? I built it, then I checked: it books the walks so brilliantly!
An older phone? The store says no, so where's compatibility?
The sign-ups soared, performance dived, and that's poor scalability!
It died at night; the dogs all cried: goodbye, reliability!
Accessibility's a mess and so is usability!
Walk cats? It cost a second app. Good grief, extensibility!
What you don't know can hurt you through a growing liability.
So leave no stone unturned, and see the whole of software quality.
Good in a dozen ways, and bad in others, though:
Fast, but it crashes; is it steady? Sound? Oh, no.
Ship it by Sunday; it's a pain to change, and slow;
Save on the checking, and the bugs can wreck the show;
Polish one part, and then another takes a blow:
Which of the "ilities" are yours? I've got to know!
Right. You want me to fix the code? Then here's what I need from it.
Confused, why can't I reproduce it? No debuggability.
I ask it why: it's "Oops". Gee, thanks for diagnosability!
I wipe the payments? Stale docs: "Nightly saves!" Recoverability?
We walk it through by hand, and miss a lot: low testability.
The blob's so huge, I burn my context: not much readability.
I patch one bug, and two more hatch: so where's maintainability?
What you don't know can hurt me too: it goes and puts me ill at ease.
You'll make my day: just name and weigh the agent-facing "ilities".
Good in a dozen ways, and bad in others, though:
Fast, but it crashes; is it steady? Sound? Oh, no.
Ship it by Sunday; it's a pain to change, and slow;
Save on the checking, and the bugs can wreck the show;
Polish one part, and then another takes a blow:
Which of the "ilities" are yours? I've got to know!
A quality dimension is a way it's good or bad,
and each is independent: that's the part that drives you mad!
And most of them are "ilities", which rhyme: a lucky break!
But some of them are not, and so I hunt, for goodness' sake:
Resilience... resilience... ...a stroke of brilliance!
Compliance... compliance... ...it's rocket science!
The "ilities"? A nickname for the family, the lot:
the ending's not the point: they're all dimensions, rhyme or not!
Upgradability, replaceability,
explainability, and traceability,
observability, reversibility,
installability, and portability,
and flexibility, detectability,
and suitability, reusability,
sustainability, and changeability,
deployability, enjoyability!
I could name you a hundred, and still not be through,
but the ones that you want? That's a question for you!
Good in a dozen ways, and bad in others, though:
Fast, but it crashes; is it steady? Sound? Oh, no.
Ship it by Sunday; it's a pain to change, and slow;
Save on the checking, and the bugs can wreck the show;
Polish one part, and then another takes a blow:
Which of the "ilities" are yours? I've got to know!